Finding Aid for the Henry Miller Papers LSC.0110
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Printed materials, 1937-1984; 14 boxes (7 linear ft.)
  - Extracts from periodicals, 1937-1983; 3.5 boxes (1.75 linear ft.)
    - Aranda, Joaquin. "Henry Miller en Castellano." Nuestro Tiempo, undated; 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 10)
    - Baxter, Annette K. "An imaginary correspondence." Ararat. (Autumn 1963): 29-35, 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 11)
      "Henry Miller and Henry James: an imaginary correspondence on the morality of the artist." Note from Annette Baxter to Henry Miller on first page.
    - Beaver, Harold. "King of smut." Books and Bookmen. (April 1979): 34-36, 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 12)
    - Bennett, John, ed. "A tribute to Henry Miller." Black Messiah. Premiere Issue. Ellensburg, WA: Vagabond Press: 1981, 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 13)
    - "Big Sur." Life Magazine. (July 6, 1959), 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 14)
      Article on Big Sur and its residents.
    - Bufano, Beniamino. "Genesis of the night life." What's Doing. n.d.: 26-27, undated; 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 15)
    - Burgess, Anthony. ["My life and times."] The New York Times Book Review. (January 2, 1972): [1], 10-11, 2 items. (Box 135, Folder 16)
      Also included: Henry Miller's "On His Sins of Omission," New York Times Book Review. (January 2, 1972): 10-11.
    - Chisholm, Hugh. "A man-sized world: letter to Henry Miller...from Hugh Chisholm in Athens, Greece", undated; 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 17)
    - Ciardi, John. "Manner of speaking." Saturday Review. (June 30, 1962): 13, 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 18)
    - Courtney, Robert. "The four letter world of Henry Miller." Rogue Magazine, undated; 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 19)
    - Crossman, Sylvie. "Henry Miller ou la jouissance." Les Cahier du Chemin. No. 25 (October 15, 1975): 148-152, 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 20)
    - Curtis, Jack. "Saving L.A. from Henry Miller." Los Angeles (May 1983): 148-153, 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 21)
    - "Dangerous devils-play." Kontakt Med Tiden. (August 1959): 416-417, 437, 1 items. (Box 135, Folder 22)
      Danish article with an English translation.
    - Fraenkel, Michael. "Bastard death." Paris: Carrefour, 1936, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 1)
      Pages 11-42 in negative photocopy. Letter to Henry Miller dated Paris, November 15, 1935.
    - Fukuzawa, Ichiro. "Water painting of Henry Miller", circa 1955; 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 2)
      Translated by Shigeo Kitano from the art and literature review "Geijutsu-Shincho," Tokyo, July 1955.
    - Gelre, Henk van. "Het fenomeen Henry Miller." [periodical unidentified], undated; 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Glicksberg, Charles I. "Literature and society." Arizona Quarterly. Vol. 8 (Summer, 1952): 128-139, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 4)
    - Haan, Jacques Den. "Big Sur en de vrede van scheveningen." Litterair Paspoort. (April 1958): 77-79, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 5)
    - Honda, Yasunori. "In quest of draco and the elliptic: Henry Miller's unwritten space fiction." Christianity and Culture. No. 15 (1982), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 6)
      Published by the Institute of Christian Culture Miyagi, Women's College, Sendai, Japan. In Japanese.
    - Hornus, Jean-Michel. "J'ai rencontré Miller, un coeur pur", undated; 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 7)
    - Judge, Jacquelyn. "Fred Lyon... happy photographer." Modern Photography. (August 1951): 37-42, 100, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 8)
    - Kazin, Alfred. "The writer as sexual show-off." New York. (June 9, 1975), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 9)
    - Knef, Hildegard. "Die knef uber Henry Miller: erist mein grosser freund." Twen. 6.9 (September, 1964): 86-88, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 10)
    - Krim, Seymour. "The netherworld of Henry Miller." The Commonweal. LVII.3 (October 24, 1952): 68-71, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 11)
    - L., Y. "Henry Miller, L'homme de la conversion." Paru. No. 22 (September 22, 1946): 43-50, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 12)
    - Lee, Alwyn. "Henry Miller: the pathology of isolation." New World Writing. (November 1952): 339-347, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 13)
    - "Libros por correo." Papeles de Sou Armadans. VII.XIX (October 1957): XIII, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 14)
    - Lingel, Fred. "Oh me oh mighty: a world to hungry artists." The Leaves Fall. 3.4 (January 1945): 94, 96, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 15)
      "A reply to Henry Miller's 'What Are You Going To Do About Alf?', published by Bern Porter, Berkeley, California."
    - Littlejohn, David. "The Tropics of Miller." New Republic. CXLVI (March 5, 1962): 31-35, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 16)
    - Lost Generation Journal. IV.3 (Winter 1976-1977), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 17)
      Includes seven articles regarding Miller and reviews of The Air-conditioned Nightmare and Book of Friends.
    - MacDonald, Edgar E. "The Childs Collection of Henry Miller at Randolph-Macon College", undated; 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 18)
      Underlining by Miller.
    - Maine, Harold. "The hour of man." Manas. IV.5. (January 31, 1951), 3 items. (Box 136, Folder 19)
    - Manning, Hugo. "Apropos of Henry Miller." The Wind and the Rain. 2.4 (Winter 1945): 166-168, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 20)
    - Martin, Jay. "'The king of smut': Henry Miller's Tragical History." The Antioch Review (1977): 342-367, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 21)
    - Martin, Jay. "Remember to remember: Henry Miller and Literary Tradition." Clio. 7.1 (1977): 75-90, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 22)
    - Milgrom, A. L. "Henry Miller and fiends." Select. (September 1961), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 23)
      Minneapolis and St. Paul.
    - Miller, Henry. "Another open letter." New Republic. (December 6, 1943): 813-814, 2 items. (Box 136, Folder 24)
    - Miller, Henry. "An appreciation." Chimera. III.I (Autumn 1944), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 25)
      Typescript copied from original.
    - Miller, Henry. "Are we going anywhere?" Art Forum. II.1 (July 1968): 27-30, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 26)
    - Miller, Henry. "Automotive passacaglia." Tomorrow. 4.11 (April 1944): 257-259., 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 27)
    - Miller, Henry. "Bastard death." New English Weekly. (December 10, 1936): 171-172, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 28)
      A letter to Michael Fraenkel (June 19, 1936).
    - Miller, Henry. "Clef hangers." Cavalier Magazine. (May 1962): 54-55, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 29)
      Text from The Colossus of Maroussi by Henry Miller.
    - Miller, Henry. "Encounter with Rank." Journal of the Otto Rank Association. 1.1 (Fall 1966), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 30)
    - Miller, Henry. "Les enfants de la terre." Les Lettres Nouvelles. (17 February 1953), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 31)
      French translation of "Children of the earth." Photocopy.
    - Miller, Henry. "The enormous womb", undated; 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 32)
    - Miller, Henry. "Glittering -pie." The Harvard Advocate. (September 1935): 22-24, 2 items. (Box 136, Folder 33)
      Two copies.
    - Miller, Henry. "A great writer's view: banning books in school is 'insane'." Journal of the New York State School Boards Association. (October 1968), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 34)
      Includes letter from Frances Richardson, managing editor.
    - Miller, Henry. "Henry Miller in conversation...an exclusive interview at 85." Interviewed by Robert Cross. Life in California. (September 1977): 26-29, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 35)
    - Miller, Henry. "The honest man..." The Nation. (March 20, 1943): 422-424, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 36)
      Review of "Andre Gide and the Crisis of Modern Thought" by Klaus Mann. Creative Age Press.
    - Miller, Henry. "The hour of man", undated; 2 items. (Box 136, Folder 37)
      Reprinted from The Chicago Review.
    - Miller, Henry. "Into the night life." New Democracy. 6.4 (June 1936): 82-85, 2 items. (Box 136, Folder 38)
      Two copies. Subtitled: "Fragment from a Novel to be Called 'Black Spring'."
    - Miller, Henry. "Is fiction?" Occident. (Spring 1950): 7-8, 2 items. (Box 136, Folder 39)
      Also photocopy of the issue of "Occident" in which the article was published.
    - Miller, Henry. "The legends of ignorance." New Republic. (August 30, 1943): 291, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 40)
      Review of Joshua Trachtenberg's "The Devil and the Jews." Published in New Haven by Yale University Press.
    - Miller, Henry. "A letter to albion moonlight." Now. (August 1941): 33-34, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 41)
    - Miller, Henry. "Letters from Colt authors: dear folks." The Colt (December 1941), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 42)
    - Miller, Henry. "A letter on Celine." Paris Review. No. 31 (Winter/Spring 1964): 137, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 43)
    - Miller, Henry. "Letter to the park commissioner", undated; 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 44)
      Signed Phineas Flapdoodle.
    - Miller, Henry. "The life and times of Henry Miller--pictorial essay." Playboy. 18.11. (November 1971), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 45)
    - Miller, Henry. "Mona." Translated by Henri Fluchère. L'Arbalète. 9 (Autumn 1944): [9]-10, 145-152, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 46)
      Extract from Tropic of Cancer.
    - Miller, Henry. "Mother and son." The Nation. (June 5, 1943), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 47)
      Review of Thomas Wolfe's "Letters to his Mother."
    - Miller, Henry. "L'obscénité et la loi de reflexion." Fontaine. 7.56 (October 1946): 334-348, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 48)
    - Miller, Henry. "Obscenity and the law of reflection." Kentucky Law Journal. 51.4 (Summer 1963): 577-590, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 49)
    - Miller, Henry. "Of art and the future." Life and Letters Today. 40.79 (March 1944): 136-150, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 50)
    - Miller, Henry. "Oh lake of light!" Harper's Bazaar. (August 1944), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 51)
    - Miller, Henry. "Portrait of General Grant." Day and Night. (December 23, 1937): 20-21, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 52)
    - Miller, Henry. "Position of the sun." View. (May 1946): 22, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 53)
      Review of Jean Giono's "Blue Boy," published by Viking Press.
    - Miller, Henry. "Preface." In "The Renegade" by Alfred Perlès. London: G. Allen and Unwin, 1943, 3 items. (Box 136, Folder 54)
      Two Photostat copies and film.
    - Miller, Henry. "Prince of Denmark." New Republic. (May 10, 1943): 642-643, 3 items. (Box 136, Folder 55)
      Review of Walter Lowrie's "A Short Life of Kierkegaard." Prinston: The Princeton University Press. 1 original, 1 Photostat copy, and one copy on film.
    - Miller, Henry. "Reading Blaise Cendrars." Mademoiselle. (October 1973): 58, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 56)
    - Miller, Henry. "Sex goes public: a talk with Henry Miller by David Dury." Esquire (May 1966): 118-121, 170-172, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 57)
    - Miller, Henry. "The shadows: the extraordinary place of the extraordinary weeks hall." Town and Country. 97 (March 1942): 42-43, 76-79, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 58)
    - Miller, Henry. "The southland." The New English Weekly. (May 24, 1945): 52-53, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 59)
    - Miller, Henry. "The storyteller." Story. XIX.91 (September-October, 1941): 70-74, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 60)
    - Miller, Henry. "Sur un livre trop vite épuisé: 'banlieue de Paris'", undated; 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 61)
    - Miller, Henry. "The tree of life and death." T'ien Hsia Monthly. 5.4 (November 1937): 377-381, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 62)
    - Miller, Henry. "'Tropic of Cancer' revisited." Playboy. 17.6 (June 1970): 133-135, 200-201, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 63)
    - Miller, Henry. "Views and reviews." The New English Weekly. 26.11 (December 28, 1944): 93-94, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 64)
    - Miller, Henry. Writings published in three issues of the journal The Leaves Fall, 1943-1945; 8 items. (Box 136, Folder 65)
      Two copies of "Fragments from an Open Letter to All and Sundry," 1.11 (August 1943): 41-44. Three copies of "Letter to Emil," 2.4 (February-March 1944): 61-62. Three copies of "Fragment From Letter of Thanksgiving," 3.1 (October 1944): 81-82.
    - Moller, Kai Fiis. "Henry Miller." Politiken. (June 7, 1957), 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 66)
      Published in Copenhagen. "Proof-copy."
    - Moricand, Conrad. "Les cinquante rames du naive ARGO." Montpellier: A La Licorne,1955, 1 items. (Box 136, Folder 67)
    - Morice-Kerné, A. "La lecture heureuse." L'école maternelle française. 35.7 (April 1958), 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 1)
    - Okumura, Osamu. "Henry Miller: an introduction." Aoyama Journal of General Education. No. 3 (1962), 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 2)
      Aoyama Gakuin University, Shibuya, Tokyo.
    - The Olympia Press. "On the old theme of literature and censorship." Paris: The Olympia Press, 1958, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - Omarr, Sidney. "Henry Miller today." Frontier. (February 1956): 20-21, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - Orwell, George. "Words and Henry Miller." Tribute (London). (February 22, 1946): 15, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 5)
    - Perlès, Alfred. "Henry Miller in Villa Seurat", undated; 2 items. (Box 137, Folder 6)
    - Perlès, Alfred. "On Goethe (letter to Henry Miller)." T'ien Hsia Monthly. (October 1938): 281-290, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Perlès, Alfred. "My friend Henry Miller: an intimate biography." New York: J. Day Co., 1956, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 8)
      Includes pages 225-255 only.
    - Porter, Bern. "Bern Porter: interviewed by Phil Nurenberg." Vagabond White Paper no. 5. Ellensburg, WA: Vagabond Press, circa 1983; 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 9)
      "Sample excerpts from a 27-hour, tape-recorded interview with Bern Porter. Taped in Belfast, Maine from August 35th through August 27th, 1980."
    - Porter, Bern. "Wherein the new order." The Leaves Fall. 2.9-10 (June-July 1944): 69-72, 3 items. (Box 137, Folder 10)
      Also in this issue, Henry Miller solicits aid from the readers in order to allow him to finish two unnamed books.
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. "Letter from the Southwest." Westways. (September 1975): 32-34, 79, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 11)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. "Remembering Henry Miller." Southwest Review, 6.2 (Spring 1981), 117-128, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 12)
    - Powell, Lawrence Clark. "To visit Monterey." Westways. (January 1976): 23-26, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 13)
    - Read, Herbert. "What England's leading critic thinks about America's most extraordinary writer." Reprinted from New English Weekly. [1946], 8 items. (Box 137, Folder 14)
    - Rode, Alex. 'Henry Miller: the novelist as liberator." Americas. (January 1966): 41-43, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 15)
    - Sabatier, Robert. "Les romans: quelques paysages Romanesque." Le Temps Des Hommes. No. VII (1959): 87-92, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 16)
      Article regarding Henry Miller's "Big Sur and the Oranges of Hieronymus Bosch."
    - Schneider, Marcel. "La chine de Puccini et le clown de Miller." N.R.F. (1968), 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 17)
    - Sunderland Arts Center. "Our America: Abraham Rattner, Henry Miller, from New York City to New Orleans by 1932 Buick, October 1940 to January 1941: a Sunderland Arts Center Exhibition." Sunderland: Ceolfrith Press, 1976, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 18)
    - Southern, Terry. "Only the beginning." The Nation, undated; 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 19)
    - Thoma, Richard. [Letter to Henry Miller]. August 18, 1944, 2 items. (Box 137, Folder 20)
      Originally written for "The Happy Rock," 1945. It was not used. Explanatory holograph note by Bern Porter at the front of one copy.
    - Voght, Docent Johan. "Miller og lesefriheten." Dagbladets Kronik. (May 15, 1957), 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 21)
      Article published in Oslo. Reprint of a newspaper article.
    - Wickes, George. "Henry Miller at seventy." Claremont Quarterly. (Winter 1962): 5-20, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 22)
    - Wickes, George. "Interview mit Henry Miller", undated; 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 23)
    - Yakovlev, L. "Literature of decay." Soviet literature. 6 (1950): 172-178, 2 items. (Box 137, Folder 24)
    - Young, Robert, Jr. "Henry Miller: Always Merry and Bright." Writer's Digest (November 1980): 31-[31], 47, 1 items. (Box 137, Folder 25)
    - Extracts from periodicals containing brief references to Miller, circa 1956-1980; 14 items. (Box 137, Folder 26)
    - Extracts from periodicals containing no Miller material (1 of 3), circa 1936-1964; ca. 20 items. (Box 137, Folder 27)
    - Extracts from periodicals containing no Miller material (2 of 3), circa 1936-1950; ca. 20 items. (Box 137, Folder 28)
    - Extracts from periodicals containing no Miller material (3 of 3), circa 1937-1951; ca. 20 items. (Box 137, Folder 29)
    - Pamphlets, articles, and reprints by various authors, w/o Miller material (1 of 4), circa 1947; 3 items. (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets, articles, and reprints by various authors, w/o Miller material (2 of 4), circa 1944-1982; 3 items. (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - Pamphlets, articles, reprints by various authors, w/o Miller material (3 of 4), circa 1950-1963; 16 items. (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets, articles, reprints by various authors, w/o Miller material (4 of 4), circa 1958-1947; 13 items. (Box 138, Folder 4)
- Artwork, 1931-1980; 8.5 oversized boxes
  This series contains artwork by Miller and artwork given to Miller by fans and friends.
  Arranged is subseries A-C as follows:
  A. Original artwork by Miller, ca. 1934-1980 (3 oversized boxes)
  B. Artwork by others, ca. 1931-1978 (5 oversized boxes)
  C. Signed prints and posters, ca. 1948-1974 (1 oversized box).
  - Original artwork by Miller, ca. 1934-1980; 3 oversized boxes
    This subseries primarily consists of original watercolors by Miller. Arranged chronologically, with undated materials at the beginning of the series. Where no title exists, a descriptive title has been provided.
    - Sevasty-sevasty, 1943; 1 items. (Box 124, Folder 1)
      Oil pastel and watercolor, 40 x 36 cm. (framed). Signed by Miller. Previous owner Bern Porter.
    - [Town with river and train], 1966; 1 items. (Box 162, Folder 4)
      Untitled watercolor, 53 x 67 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 6/66.
    - [Four nude figures], undated; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 1)
      Watercolor, 30 x 23 cm.
    - [Two-sided watercolor with figures and abstract landscape], undated; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 2)
      Untitled watercolor, 23 x 15 cm.
    - [Face with red cheeks and blue background], undated; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 3)
      Untitled watercolor, 50 x 33 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 48-32. Verso reveals part of an earlier, discarded work.
    - [Trees], undated; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 4)
      Untitled watercolor, 46 x 31 cm. Greek alphabet on verso.
    - [Three clothed figures], undated; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 5)
      Untitled watercolor, 51 x 36 cm. Greek vocabulary in pencil on verso.
    - [Red, green and brown abstract], undated; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 6)
      Untitled watercolor, 45 x 30 cm. Greek vocabulary in black ink on verso.
    - [Grey rectangle], undated; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 7)
      Untitled watercolor, 46 x 30. Greek vocabulary in black ink on verso.
    - The grey hat, 1934; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 8)
      Watercolor and pastel, 36 x 27 cm. Signed by Miller. Title from Miller's book of watercolors, "Echolalia."
    - Looking towards the Gare d'Orsay, 1937?; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 9)
      Watercolor, 15 x 20 cm. Inscribed on verso by Miller: "For Bern Porter from Henry Miller 2/14/44. Done in Paris (Villa Seurat)."
    - Goliath, 1938; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 10)
      Watercolor, 20 x 14 cm. Signed by Miller. Inscribed on verso by Miller: "For Bern Porter from Henry Miller 2/14/44. Done in Paris (Villa Seurat)."
    - Proposed cover for Money and How it Gets That Way, circa 1938-1944; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 11)
      Ink and pastel sketch, 30 x 25 cm.
    - Totem and taboo, 1943; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 12)
      Watercolor, 36 x 26. Signed by Miller. Pencil sketches on recto. Title from Miller's book of watercolors, "Echolalia."
    - Proposed cover for Semblance of a Devoted Past, circa 1944; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 13)
      Watercolor, 37 x 30 cm. Inscribed on verso by Miller: "For Bern Porter. Proposed cover for Semblance."
    - Self-Portrait, 1944; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 14)
      Original pen and ink sketch, 26 x 21. Inscribed on verso by Miller: "Self-Portrait, 1944 for Bern Porter."
    - Remember to remember, 1946; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 15)
      Original pen and ink sketch, 28 x 27 cm. Signed by Miller. Inscribed on recto by Miller: "For Paul Ogden from Henry Miller, 12/46." With one letter by Miller to Ogden explaining the illustrative purpose of the image.
    - [Mountains], 1957; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 16)
      Watercolor, 42 x 34 cm. Signed by Miller, dated 12/57. Inscribed by Miller on recto: "For Barbara from her Daddy, 1/4/55."
    - La vie en rose, 1961; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 17)
      Watercolor, 40 x 30 cm. Self portrait, signed by Miller.
    - Gott ist die liebe, 1961; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 18)
    - [Abstract patterns], 1980; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 19)
      Unititled watercolor, 51 x 36 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 15/80.
    - [Abstract patterns], 1980; 1 items. (Box 165, Folder 20)
      Untititled watercolor, 41 x 31 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 18/80.
    - [Self portrait for Mary de Wolf], 1949; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 1)
      Untitled watercolor, 62 x 46 cm. Signed by Miller, and numbered 28-49.
    - Ah, hapless birdee, thou wilt fly no more!, 1959; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 2)
      Watercolor, 61 x 48 cm. Signed by Miller, and numbered 11/59.
    - [Seascape with three boats], 1959; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 3)
      Untitled watercolor, 60 x 48. Signed by Miller and numbered 12/59.
    - [Town with hills in background], 1959; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 4)
      Untitled watercolor, 60 x 48 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 12/59.
    - [Nude figure, horse, and Miller's head], 1962; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 5)
      Untitled watercolor, 51 x 41 cm. Signed by Miller and dated.
    - Nude seated, 1963; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 6)
      Watercolor, 61 x 48 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 94/63.
    - The lion of Judah, 1963; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 7)
      Watercolor, 61 x 48 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 95/63.
    - [Half-length portrait of nude woman], 1963; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 8)
      Untitled watercolor, 61 x 48 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 133/63.
    - Scherzo, 1963; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 9)
      Watercolor, 61 x 48. Signed by Miller and numbered 141/63.
    - [Half-length portrait of two figures], 1965; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 10)
      Untitled watercolor, 60 x 46. Inscribed by Miller on recto: "For Barbara, Happy Birthday." Signed by Miller and numbered 34/65 [?].
    - [Floating head with abstract shapes], 1980; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 11)
      Untitled watercolor, 60 x 45 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 19/80.
    - [Abstract figure], 1980; 1 items. (Box 166, Folder 12)
      Untited watercolor, 60 x 45 cm. Signed by Miller and numbered 22/80.
  - Artwork by others, ca. 1931-1978; 3 oversized boxes, 2 cartons
    This subseries consists of drawings, paintings, sculptures, and prints given to Miller by fans, friends, and other artists. Notable artists include Alfred Perlès, May Ray, Abram Krol, Jean Verame, and Gyula Zilzer. Works are arranged alphabetically by the artist's surname.
    - Marrakech, Figen. [Abstract watercolor paintings], 1968; 4 items. (Box 104)
      Some signed by the author. One inscribed, "For Henry Miller, done at his home."
    - Verame, Jean. Pour l'anniversaire de Henry; I'm just wild about Henry, 1963, 1967; 2 items. (Box 104, Folder 1)
      Original watercolors, 40 x 32 and 80 x 55 cm. Signed by the artist.
    - [Suiouin, F.?] Series of six prints, 1970; 6 items. (Box 104, Folder 2)
      50 x 64 cm. Signed by the artist